Abhishek Sharma

https://bit.ly/abhpf ■ abhisheksharma131098@gmail.com | 🖫 +919852240467 +919518609407

EDUCATION

B.TECH IN CATION ENGINEERING

2017 - 2021 | Haryana Haryana Engineering College Kurukshetra University Marks: 75.1%

LINKS

Portfolio: bit.ly/abhpf

Github: abhisheksharma1310

in LinkedIn: abhisheksharma1310

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

JavaScript

FRONT-END

Html • Css • Bootstrap DOM • Jquery • ReactJs

BACK-END

Linux • NodeJs • ExpressJs Eis • Rest APIs

DATABASE

MongoDb

CLOUD

Firebase • GCP • Azure

OTHER

Git • Figma • Canva

PROJECTS

Memories Blog: open

Chat app: open Box Office: open

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with experience in building, debugging, testing, maintaining, **ELECTRONICS AND COMMUNI-** and deploying web applications. My proficiency in using technologies such as HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, and ExpressJS, coupled with my strong problemsolving, analytical skills and passion for learning new technologies, make me an asset to any development team.

EXPERIENCE

JETSONS ROBOTICS I FULL STACK WEB DEVELOPER

Jan 2022 - Present | New Delhi

- Developed and maintained web applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, ReactJS, NodeJS, ExpressJS, and MongoDB database.
- Integrated and used state management libraries like Redux for data flow and state management in React web apps.
- Created REST APIs in the backend using NodeJS and ExpressJS and connected its endpoint with frontend React web apps using Axios.
- Integrated Firebase services such as Authentication, Firestore, RTBDs, Storage, and Firebase Function to frontend as well as backend.
- Integrated Google auths in frontend for user account creation, Authentication, and authorization to the backend using JWT.
- Connected and used MongoDB database to backend server Nodejs.
- Implemented react hooks, custom hooks, UI libraries such as Material UI and React Suite, and navigation libraries such as react-router in React web apps.
- Debugged and resolved issues related to web applications.
- Conducted tests on web applications and ensured their proper functioning.
- Collaborated with the team to develop and deploy web applications.
- Implemented new features to improve the overall functionality of web apps.
- Maintained the quality of web applications by ensuring their smooth performance and user-friendliness.

JETSONS ROBOTICS | Web Developer - Intern

July 2021 - Dec 2021 | New Delhi

- Developed Frontend web apps with Reactis.
- Integrated and consumed back-end microservices, and Rest APIs on UI.
- Maintained git repositories of web development projects on GitHub and BitBucket.

CERTIFICATION & TRAINING

REACTJS

INTERNSHALA - 2022 certificate: view score: 94%

NODEJS

INTERNSHALA - 2023

certificate: view score: 100%